Los Angeles Institute of Contemporary Art
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Exhibitions and Programs, 1974-1987, Series 5:; (Boxes 3-13; 9.5 linear feet)
  - Exhibition Files, 1974-1987, 5.2
    - John Maggiotto, August 1983 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Art and Language, September 1983-October 1983, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
      Michael Baldwin, Mel Ramsden
    - Philip Hefferton, September 1983-October 1983 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - LAICA After Hours Video Night, September 1983 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Sabina Ott, September 1983-October 1983 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Luis E. Serrano, September 1983-October 1983 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Cabin, Temple, Trailer, November 1983-December 1983, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 46-47)
      Curated by Charles Moore
    - Cabin, Temple, Trailer, November 1983-December 1983, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
    - Steve Heino, November 1983-December 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Mako Idemitsu, November 1983-December 1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Julius, November 1983-December 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Lavi Daniel, January 1984-March 1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Charles Gaines, January 1984-February 1984 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Les Levine, January 1984-February 1984, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Il Modo Italiano, January 1984-April 1984, (24 folders) (Box 8, Folder 14-37)
      Alighiero Boetti
      Alik Cavaliere
      Luciano Fabro
      Jannis Kounellis
      Mario Merz
      Marisa Merz
      Luigi Otani
      Mimmo Paladino
      Giulio Paolini
      Antonio Paradiso
      Guiseppe Penone
      Co-organized by Germano Celant
    - Il Modo Italiano, January 1984-April 1984, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
    - Michael Scroggins, February 1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Big Candy, March 1984-April 1984, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
      Franco Assetto
    - Laura Josephson, March 1984-April 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Julia Kidd, March 1984-April 1984 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Tony Oursler, March 1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - John Rodgers, March 1984-April 1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Tony Labat, April 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Mari Border, May 1984-June 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - John Frame, May 1984-June 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Llyn Foulkes and Martin Mull, May 1984-June 1984 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Australia: Nine Contemporary Artists, July 1984-August 1984, (21 folders) (Box 9, Folder 17-37)
      Michael Callaghan (Redback Graphix)
      Greg Collins (Redback Graphix)
      John Davis
      John Dunkley-Smith
      Marr Grounds
      Lyndal Jones
      John Nixon
      Mike Parr
      Stelarc
    - Music Video/Video Music, July 1984 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - When the Conversation Turns to Art, September 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      John Knight
    - Four Installations, October 1984-November 1984, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
      Richard Baker, Charles Ray, Laurie Sing, Fred Tomaselli
    - Divisions: Seven Los Angeles Painters, December 1984-January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Edith Baumann-Hudson
      Jerry Brainin
      Jeff Falsgraf
      Scot Heywood
      Penny Krebs
      Rick La Fleur
      Alan Wayne
    - Richard Joseph, December 1984-January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cathy Lightfoot, December 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Video 74/84: the Event of a Decade, December 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Art and Sex, January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Robert Jaye, Lynn Leatart
    - Karen Atkinson, February 1985-March 1985 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Antonio Mutadas, February 1985-March 1985 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Secular Attitudes, February 1985-March 1985, (5 folders) (Box 10, Folder 11-15)
      Jenny Holzer, Fred Lonidier, The Sisters of Survival
    - L.A.: Recent Designs in Fashion and Furniture, April 1985-May 1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    - Eve Laramee, December 1984-January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - B and W, June 1985-July 1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
      Auste
      Ericka Beckman
      Dana Duff
      Nancy Dwyer
      Mike Glier
      Bill Komoski
      John Mandel
      Paul McCarthy
      Matt Mullican
      Raymond Pettibon
      Jim Shaw
    - Alyse Green Edwards, June 1985-July 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Michael Gonzales, June 1985-July 1985 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Tim Ebner, Ned Evans, and Renee Petropoulos, December 1984-January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Proof and Perjury, August 1985-October 1985 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      Dennis Balk
      Uta Barth
      David Cunningham
      Larry Johnson
      Luciano Perna
      Claudia Walther
    - Nancy Evans, September 1985-October 1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Microgallery, September 1985-October 1985 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - The Residents and Harold Budd, October 1985-November 1985 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Pacific Connections, November 1985-December 1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
      Takako Araki
      Luis Bermudez
      Ron Cooper
      Philip Cornelius
      Susan Curry
      Roseline Delisle
      Hideyuki Hayashi
      Satoru Hoshino
      Keiji Ito
      Rikichi Miyanaga
      Hiroaki Morino
      Gifford Myers
      Kimpei Nakamura
      Elsa Rady
      Tadayasu Sasayama
      Adrian Saxe
      Osamu Suzuki
      Masamichi Yoshikawa
    - Sculpture (Part One and Two), January 1986-April 1986 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - House Monument, April 1986-May 1986 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      Kate Ericson, Mel Ziegler
    - Lectio Divina, October 1986-November 1986 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      Jeff Matsuno
    - 5th and Fig., January 1987 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      Krzystof Wodiczko
    - Projections in Public, February 1987 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Janet Delaney
      Tom Ferentz
      Jeanne Finley
      Nancy Floyd
      Linda Tadic
      Kevin White
    - Unknown Exhibits, mid 1970s-mid 1980s (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Proposed Exhibits (Box 10)
      - Vito Acconci, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - Ida Applebroog, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - Art in Public Places, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Art Materialized, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 39)
        Charles Fahlen
        Sam Gilliam
        Roy Lichtenstein
        Roy Maconnel
        Phillip Mayberry
        Miriam Shapiro
        Ned Smyth
      - Daniel Aulagnier, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 40)
      - Paul Beattie, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 41)
      - Joyce Baronio, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 42)
      - Sandra Binion, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 43)
      - Jonathan Borofsky, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 44)
      - Anne Bray, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 45)
      - John Blake, circa 1981 (Box 10, Folder 46)
      - Chris Burden, early 1980s (Box 10, Folder 47)
      - CAPS/ICI 1981 Traveling Video Festival, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 48)
      - Cave Canen Book Project, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 49)
      - Cedars-Sinai Medical Center, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 50)
      - Bruce Chao, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 51)
      - Carl Cheng, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Harold Cohen, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Paz Cohen, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Collaborations, circa 1982, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
      - Douglas Davis, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Nicola De Maria and Edward Moses, circa 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - East/West, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Pete Evaristo, circa 1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Jud Fine, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Fluxus, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Luis Frangella, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - [furniture], 1982 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Generic Structure, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Jon Gibson, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Dennis Gillingwater, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Philip Glass, Elyse Grinstein, and Richard Serra, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Coco Gordon, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Mineko Grimmer, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Elyse Grinstein (see Philip Glass, Elyse Grinstein, and Richard Serra), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Heidi Hardin, circa 1982 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Anthony Hernandez (see Richard Turner and Anthony Hernandez), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Margaret Honda, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - [Independent Contemporary Exhibition], 1982 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - James Irwin, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Risa Jaroslow, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Allan Kaprow, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Harry Kipper, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Bill Kominski, John Miller, Megan Williams, circa 1981 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Kronos Quartet, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - John Lees, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Living Spaces, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Michael C. McMillen, circa 1982 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - John Miller (Bill Komonski, John Miller, and Megan Williams), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Tim Miller, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - [miscellaneous photographs], circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Edward Moses (see Nicola De Maria and Edward Moses), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Jac Mote, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Michael Myers, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Narcissism in Contemporary Art, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 40)
        David Bowie
        David Hockney
        Cindy Sherman
        Andy Warhol
      - Barbara Noah, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Olympic Arts Festival, 1984, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 42-44)
      - Other/Strategies, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 45)
        Nancy Barton
        Kathe Burkhardt
        Connie Hatch
        Julia Kidd
        Sherry Millner
        Gail Rebhan
        Erika Suderberg
        Carrie Weems
        Millie Wilson
      - A Painting Show, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 46)
        Marcia Hafif
        Peter Joseph
        Bob Law
        Carmen Gloria Morales
        Olivier Mosset
        Tomoharu Murakami
        Robert Ryman
        Frederic Thurz
        Gunter Umberg
      - The Pinhole Image, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 47)
        Clarissa Carnell
        Barbara Esher
        Jim Haberman
        Mary Sayer Howard
        Martha Maddigan
        Mary Ruth Moore
        Dale Quarterman
        Eric Renner
        Wiley Sanderson
        Ruth Thorne-Thomsen
        Willie Anne Wright
      - Poets and Painters, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 48)
        Thaisa Frank
        Steve Galloway
        Amy Gerstler
        Lyn Hixon
        Rita Valencia
        Paul Vangilisti
        Benjamin Weissman
        Stanley Wilson
      - Public Contexts, 1982-1987 (Box 11, Folder 49)
        Allan Kaprow
      - Roland Reiss, circa 1984 (Box 11, Folder 50)
      - Sex and Violence, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 52)
      - Sculpture From Germany, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 53)
        Joseph Beuys
        Isa Genzken
        Rebecca Horn
        Wolfgang Nestler
        Ulrich Ruckriem
        Reiner Ruthenbeck
        Barbara Schmidt-Heins
        Thomas Schutte
        Franz Erhard Walther
        Stefan Werwerka
      - The Science Club, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 54)
        Larry Albright
        Henry Beer
        Daniel Brady
        Doug Campbell
        Philip Garner
        Ray Harryhausen
        Craig Hodgetts
        Mike Mandel
        Doug Michels
        Tom Shannon
        Mark Stock
        Larry Sultan
      - Richard Serra (see Philip Glass, Elyse Grinstein, Richard Serra), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - Stuart Sherman, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 56)
      - Buster Simpson, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 57)
      - 60s Avant Garde in Southern California, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 58)
      - Alexis Smith, circa 1983 (Box 11, Folder 59)
      - Michael Smith, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Alan Sonfist, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Southern California Women's Caucus For Art, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - Peter Taylor, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 63)
      - Richard Teitelbaum, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 64)
      - 3 x 3, mid 1980s (Box 11, Folder 65)
      - Richard Turner and Anthony Hernandez, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - Johanna Went, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Megan Williams (see Bill Komoski, John Miller, and Megan Williams), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - Young British Photographers, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 69)
        David Buckland
        Paul Graham
        Chris Jennings
        Dick Jewell
        Sharon Kivland
        Maureen Paley
        Jan Turvey
        Boyd Webb
  - Program Files, 1975-1986, 5.3
    Found here are files documenting LAICA's public programming and special events, such as lectures, conferences, fund-raising events, films, dinners, concerts, and book sales. Individual files for each program or event include a wide variety of materials, including flyers, pamphlets and brochures, announcements, press releases, resumes, budgets, sales records, grant applications, and correspondence.
    Files documenting LAICA's CETA-funded Artist-in-Residence program are found here. Among the participating artists were Peter Alexander, Vija Celmins, and Allen Ruppersberg. Files for LAICA's Artist Registry of Southern California artists typically consist of biographical information and representative slides and/or photographs of representative artwork.
    Program files have been arranged in chronological order by the month the event took place. Slides have been filed in Series 8, Slides.
    - Special Events (Box 11)
      - T-Shirt Extravaganza, September 1975 (Box 11, Folder 70)
      - New Dimensions of Reality, January 1976-March 1976 (Box 11, Folder 71)
        Organized by Barbara Smith
        Holton Arp
        Carroll Carlson
        Elsa Garmire
        Gordon Garmire
        Antoinetta Lilly
        John Lilly
        Gary Lunch
        Louis Narens
        Robert Sinsheimer
        Edward Wortz
      - William Wegman, February 1977 (Box 11, Folder 72)
      - Robert Irwin, June 1977 (Box 11, Folder 73)
      - Fun Dance and Artists' Jam, August 1977 (Box 11, Folder 74)
      - Open House, September 1977 (Box 11, Folder 75)
      - Claire Copley, October 1977 (Box 11, Folder 76)
      - Fund Raiser, October 1977 (Box 11, Folder 77)
      - A Textual Analysis of Robert Frank's Book The Americans, January 1978 (Box 11, Folder 78)
        John Brumfield
      - Edit De Ak and Walter Robinson, February 1978 (Box 11, Folder 79)
      - Gerry Rosen, February 1978 (Box 11, Folder 80)
      - The Ethics and Economics of Performance Art, March 1978 (Box 11, Folder 81)
        Cheri Gaulke
        Leslie Labowitz Straus
        Claire Spark
      - Louisiana Cajuns, March 1978 (Box 11, Folder 82)
        Turner Browne
      - Lowell Darling, April 1978 (Box 11, Folder 83)
      - The New Artspace Conference, April 1978 (Box 11, Folder 84)
      - Contemporary Art Tour of Italy, May 1978-June 1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - New Vocal Techniques in the Arts, October 1978-December 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Watts Towers Arts Center Lectures, November 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        Peter Alexander, Carole Caroompas, Richard Newton
      - Christmas Sale, December 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Downtown Artist Meeting, December 1978, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
      - Seminar on Art Criticism, December 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Christopher Knight, Susan Larsen, Louise Lewis, Peter Plagens, Melinda Wortz
      - Jackie Appel, February 1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Lewis Baltz, February 1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Peter Schjeldahl, February 1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - LAICA Sells Out, March 1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Art Run, April 1978 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Maria Nordman, May 1979-July 1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Films by Babeth, Sandy Daley, Robert Mapplethorpe, and Ed Ruscha, June 1979 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Urban Alterations, November 1979 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        Robert Janz, Ann Preston, Moira Sheehan, Judy Simonian
      - Art in the Afternoon, December 1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Carla Stellweg, December 1979 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Typesetting Service, circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Southern California, May 1980-June 1980 (Box 12, Folder 19)
        Louis Hock
      - The Empire Strikes Back, June 1980 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Bicentennial Block Party, December 1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Richard Ralph Roehl, November 1980 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Rock For Art, February 1981 (Box 12, Folder 23)
        The B-People, The Boneheads, The Suburban Lawns, The Urinals
      - In and Around Little Tokyo, April 1981 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - LAICA Sells Out, April 1981 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Orestes and the Three Furious Ladies, May 1981 (Box 12, Folder 26)
        Lloyd Hamrol, Melya Kaplan, Evris Tsakirides
      - Games People Play, June 1981 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - LAICA Journal Celebration, June 1981 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Three Films by Stelarc, August 1981 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Fashion Moda, October 1981 (Box 12, Folder 30)
        Joe Lewis
      - Dustin Shuler and Bob Curry, September 1982-October 1982 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - Instant Collection, October 1982 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - Progressive Dinner, October 1982 (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Germano Celant, November 1982 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Official Fine Art Posters of the 1984 Olympic Games, January 1983 (Box 12, Folder 35-36)
        Carlos Almaraz
        Jennifer Bartlett
        Billy Al Bengston
        Jonathan Borofsky
        Sam Francis
        April Greiman
        Jamie Odgers
        Martin Puryear
        Robert Rauschenberg
        Raymond Saunders
      - Doumani House Tour, circa March 1983 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Gathering in Support of LAICA, July 1983 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - LAICA After Hours Video Night, circa September 1983 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - Romantic Comedy, October 1983 (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - Champagne Tasting, November 1983 (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - Trumps, circa November 1983 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - Art Sale, March 1984, April 195-May 1985, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 43-45)
      - High Tea and Concert, July 1984 (Box 12, Folder 46)
      - Flowers of Life For Central America, October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - The World of Gilbert and George, October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - Book Sale, December 1984 (Box 12, Folder 49)
      - Frederick R. Weisman Art Collection Tour, June 1985 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      - Fashion Show, February 1986 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Proposed Programs (Box 12)
      - The Artist, circa mid 1970s (Box 12, Folder 52)
        Jerry Anderson
        Greg Card
        Gary Lloyd
        Alan McCullum
        Beyte Saar
        John Schroeder
        Barbara Smith
        Connie Zehr
      - Women in Art, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 53)
        Max Cole
        Clare Falkenstein
        Ruth Iskin
        Connie Jenkins
        Beverly O'Neill
        Vaughan Rachel
        Arlene Raven
        June Wayne
        Wanda Westcoast
        Melinda Wortz
      - Thomas McEvilley, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - CETA Artist in Residence (Box 12)
      - Larry Albright, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 55)
      - Peter Alexander, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 56)
      - Ed Cabajal, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 57)
      - Vija Celmins, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 58)
      - Anthony Hernandez, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 59)
      - Bob Gibson, circa 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 60)
      - Pat Hogan, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 61)
      - Mark Kaiserman, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 62)
      - Maria Kwong, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 63)
      - Leslie Labowitz Straus, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 64)
      - Jilly Lauren, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 65)
      - Peter Lodato, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 66)
      - John Miller, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 67)
      - Tommy Nation, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 68)
      - Allen Ruppersburg, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 69)
      - Doni Silver, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 70)
      - Judy Simonian, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 71)
      - Jean Thrift, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 72)
      - Bob Wilhite, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 73)
      - Richard Yokomi, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - Artist Registry, circa 1976 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Artist Files, circa 1980s, 5.4
    This subseries consists of general materials collected by LAICA about contemporary artists, as well as scattered correspondence with artists. Slides have been filed in Series 8, Slides.
    - "A," circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - "B-C," circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - "D-E," circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - "F-H," circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - "I-K," circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - "L-Mc," circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - "Mi-R," circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "S," circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "T-Z," circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Publications, 1974-1987, Series 6:; (Boxes 13-15; 2.75 linear feet)
  Files documenting the production, editing, and publication of LAICA's quarterly Journal are found here, as well as copies of LAICA's newsletter. The Journal focused primarily on contemporary Southern California visual arts and culture, and included essays, interviews, artwork, and fiction. The cover of each issue depicted artwork specifically commissioned for the magazine. Notable writers and curators published in the Journal include Frances Colpitt, Mike Kelley, Peter Plagens, and Peter Schjeldahl.
  The files contain records of the publication committee which include correspondence, editorial and production files, financial information, advertising files, and copies of several issues of the magazine.
  Also found here is a complete run of LAICA's in-house newsletter and one issue of a publication entitled Artist Calendar.
  This series is arranged into 3 subseries:
  6.1: Committee Files, 1974-1987
  6.2: Journal, 1981-1987
  6.3: Printed Materials, 1974-1986
  - Committee Files, 1974-1987, 6.1
    This subseries consists of administrative and financial records relating to LAICA's publications, primarily the Journal.
    - Budgets, 1981-1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Catalog Exchange List, December, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Consignment Sheets, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Contracts and Agreements, early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1987, (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 8-13)
    - Distribution Records, early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Income Sources, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Invoice Book, 1975-1986 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Job Descriptions, circa 1974-early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Journal Fact Sheets, early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Journal Mechanical Requirements, early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1983-1987 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Publication Lists, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Rates, early 1980s (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Subscription Cards, late 1970s (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Journal, 1981-1987, 6.2
    This subseries consists of the editorial files relating to the Journal. Files include proposals, correspondence, interview transcripts, manuscript drafts and final copy. Of special interest is an unedited transcript of an interview with Bruce Nauman in 1982, and unedited transcripts of oral history interviews with LAICA staff members (see "Interviews" by Robert Pincus in issue #40).
    The files have been arranged in chronological order by issue number, and then organized by the order of that issue's contents. Manuscripts written for or published in unknown issues have been placed at the end of this subseries.
    - Issue #29 (Box 13)
      - Editorial Materials, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Issue #30 (Box 13)
      - Editorial Materials, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Issue #31 (Box 13)
      - Artist Biographical Materials and Statements, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 26-27)
      - Editorial Materials, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - "L.A. Demystified" by Peter Schjeldahl, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - "Schjeldahl Demystified" by Peter Plagens, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 30)